PERSONS, PLACES, ORGANIZATIONS AND EVENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS
이 드라마에 나오는 인물, 장소, 조직 , 사건은 허구입니다.
THE WORST OF EVIL
최악의 악
2 YEARS AGO, 1994 SEOUL, SOUTH KOREA
2년 전, 1994년 대한민국 서울
- Hello.
- 안녕하세요.
You best.
당신이 최고입니다.
Did you feel sorry for the street vendor again?
또 노점상한테 미안한 마음이 들었나요?
No, I bought it because it tastes good.
아니요, 맛있으니까 샀어요.
- It does. - Yes.
- 그렇습니다. - 예.
What's with the uniform?
유니폼은 어쩌고?
I told you, I'm transferring to the security department.
아까 보안부서로 이동한다고 말했잖아.
Was it today?
오늘이었나요?
Let us eat.
먹자.
She transfers to the security department,
그녀는 보안 부서로 이동하고,
marking the official start of her elite career.
그녀의 엘리트 경력의 공식적인 시작을 의미합니다 .
You know that, right?
그거 알지?
Yes of course.
물론이죠.
It is worth celebrating
축하할 가치가 있는 일이다
with the whole family.
온 가족과 함께.
Your wife has been selected for Seoul
당신의 아내는 서울로 선발되었습니다
and promoted to police assistant.
그리고 경찰 조수로 승진했다.
Have you spoken to your father recently?
최근에 아버지와 통화한 적이 있나요?
No.
아니요.
Well, he's getting old,
글쎄, 그 사람도 늙어가는구나.
so he should pull himself together
그러니 그 사람은 정신을 차려야 해
and live healthy.
그리고 건강하게 살아요.
And.
그리고.
Okay.
좋아요.
How are the preparations for the promotion exam going?
승진시험 준비는 어떻게 되어가고 있나요 ?
I should prepare, but it's hard to find time.
준비해야 하는데 시간이 안나네요.
So give yourself time for it.
그러니 스스로에게 시간을 투자하세요.
Your wife is an elite cop.
당신의 아내는 엘리트 경찰입니다.
And you're just a low-level detective.
그리고 당신은 단지 하급 탐정일 뿐입니다.
- What? - Now stop that nonsense.
- 무엇? - 이제 말도 안되는 소리는 그만둬요.
Nonsense?
무의미한 말?
Don't be so condescending. As if you are much older.
너무 겸손하지 마십시오. 마치 당신이 훨씬 나이가 많은 것처럼.
Your new title doesn't mean you're mature.
새로운 직함은 당신이 성숙하다는 것을 의미하지 않습니다.
As I always say,
제가 늘 말했듯이,
if KNPU accepted women when I applied to university,
제가 대학에 지원했을 때 KNPU가 여성을 받아들였다면 ,
I would also be the boss now.
나도 이제 사장이 될 것이다.
Then that's enough.
그렇다면 충분합니다.
Enjoy your drink
마음껏 즐겨보세요
and stay as long as you want.
원하는 만큼 오래 머물 수 있습니다.
I'm going to the hospital to visit your mother.
나는 네 어머니를 만나러 병원에 갈 거야.
- I'll drive you. - No thank you.
- 내가 운전해줄게. - 아니요 괜찮습니다.
It didn't help you to close the case.
사건을 종결하는 데 도움이 되지 않았습니다.
If you wanted to go to Seoul, you should have come to
서울에 가고 싶으면 서울 로 왔어야지
retirement ceremony,
퇴직식,
have socialized…
사회화됐어???
My brothers are such idiots.
내 형제들은 정말 바보들이다.
We don't need to come again.
우리는 다시 올 필요가 없습니다.
I'd rather visit my mother than come here.
여기 오는 것보다 어머니를 방문하는 것이 더 낫습니다 .
How's your mother? Is she okay?
어머니는 좀 어떠세요? 그 사람 괜찮아요?
Yes, she's okay.
네, 괜찮아요.
Just forget what my father said about your father.
내 아버지가 네 아버지에 대해 한 말은 잊어버리렴.
I forgot about it too.
나도 잊어버렸어요.
It is from my church in high school.
제가 고등학교 다닐 때 교회에서 온 것입니다.
I should take it home.
집에 가져가야겠어요.
GANGNAM, SOUTH KOREA
대한민국 강남
Come to our club!
우리 클럽으로 오세요!
Come to All Night Club! Free beer for the ladies.
올나이트클럽으로 오세요! 여성을 위한 무료 맥주.
Stop. Damn.
멈추다. 젠장.
You bitch!
이년아!
Why aren't you working? Come here.
왜 일하지 않습니까? 이리 오세요.
- Hello. - It's annoying.
- 안녕하세요. - 짜증나.
Friends, it's: "Come to the All Night Club."
친구 여러분, "올 나이트 클럽으로 오세요."입니다.
Are you there?
여보세요?
Seriously, what are you doing?
진심으로, 뭐하는거야?
Want to make Gicheul go crazy?
기철을 미치게 만들고 싶어?
DJ CHEOLI
DJ철리
Hey, Superstar Lee!
안녕하세요, 슈퍼스타 리님!
Hey what's up?
무슨 일이야?
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
- Well? - The girls are hot today.
- 잘? - 오늘 여자들은 섹시해요.
Just look.
그냥보세요.
- Hello! - He is so sweet!
- 안녕하세요! - 그는 정말 다정해요!
She was right in front of us!
그녀는 우리 바로 앞에 있었다!
He stepped on me first!
그 사람이 나를 먼저 밟았어!
Hello.
안녕하세요.
If you want to show muscle, do it in your hometown.
근육을 보여주고 싶다면 고향에서 하세요.
In Gangnam you clap and drink.
강남에서는 박수를 치며 술을 마신다.
If you don't want to die.
죽고 싶지 않다면.
Let's change the mood with something gentle.
부드러운 것으로 분위기를 바꿔보자.
Okay. Let's lead these gentlemen outside.
좋아요. 이 신사들을 밖으로 데리고 나가자.
Next round.
다음 라운드.
Rumor has it,
소문은있다,
that you were born and raised here,
당신은 여기서 태어나고 자랐습니다.
has a good network and can fight.
좋은 네트워크를 가지고 있고 싸울 수 있습니다.
So why do you work as a DJ?
그럼 왜 DJ로 일하시나요?
Let's work together.
같이 일하자.
I want to work with real locals from Gangnam.
실제 강남 지역 주민들 과 함께 일하고 싶습니다 .
Why be a DJ in a nightclub,
나이트클럽에서 DJ가 되는 이유
when you could own one?
언제 소유할 수 있었나요?
I can make it happen.
나는 그것을 실현할 수 있습니다.
Do you think so?
그렇게 생각?
When will you make me the owner?
언제 나를 주인으로 만들어 주실 건가요?
- Are you busy? - I want to make money quickly.
- 바쁘세요? - 빨리 돈을 벌고 싶다.
Are you poor?
당신은 가난합니까?
Do you think everyone in Gangnam is rich?
강남 사람들은 다 부자인 것 같나요?
You fucking rich.
당신은 부자입니다.
Speak nicely.
친절하게 말하세요.
Young Gicheul.
영기철.
If you get all your friends to work here,
친구들을 다 여기서 일하게 하면
I make you the owner.
나는 당신을 주인으로 만듭니다.
Does that sound good?
좋은 것 같나요?
Do I have your word?
약속이 있나요?
My word?
내 글?
Is that what you want?
너가 원하는게 그거야?
Is it?
그렇습니까?
A YEAR LATER, 1995 GANGNAM, SOUTH KOREA
1년 후, 1995년 한국 강남
- Hello, Mr. - Hello.
- 안녕하세요, 선생님 - 안녕하세요.
- Enjoy it. - Yes.
- 즐겨보세요. - 예.
Good day, boss.
좋은 하루 되세요, 보스.
Did you find her?
그녀를 찾았나요?
It's Professor Yoon.
윤교수님 입니다.
I hear she's the best.
그녀가 최고라고 들었습니다.
Have you met her?
그녀를 만난 적이 있나요?
Yes, but I was told she is retired.
네, 그런데 그 사람이 은퇴했다고 들었어요 .
Money can solve everything.
돈이 모든 것을 해결할 수 있습니다.
Keep in touch with her.
그녀와 계속 연락하세요.
Bleach, boss.
블리치, 보스.
Gicheul!
기철!
We need you down below.
아래에 당신이 필요합니다.
What happens?
무슨 일이야?
Pardon. Come down.
뭐라고요. 내려와.
Get up you damn bitch.
일어나라 이 빌어먹을 년아.
- Hello. - Seriously, stop!
- 안녕하세요. - 정말이지, 그만둬!
Vent...
벤트...
You little...
이 작은...
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
You annoying bitch.
짜증나는 년아.
Pour it up, I said!
부어주세요!
No, don't.
아니, 하지 마세요.
He is from a rich family.
그는 부유한 집안 출신이다.
Beat me.
나를 이길.
Hit me now, you pig.
지금 당장 때려라, 이 돼지야.
That idiot can't even beat me.
그 바보는 나를 이길 수도 없습니다.
Who are the losers?
패자는 누구입니까?
How dare you?
어떻게 감히?
Hey.
여기요.
Do you know who I am?
내가 누군지 아세요?
Take them here and step.
여기로 가져가세요.
Step.
단계.
Din nar.
딘 나르.
Do you think our boss brought you in so you could do this?
우리 상사가 당신이 이 일을 하려고 당신을 데려왔다고 생각하시나요 ?
Your lousy DJ.
당신의 형편없는 DJ.
Light my cigarette.
담배에 불을 붙여주세요.
And what's wrong with you?
그리고 당신에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
Are you Gen X or what?
당신은 X세대인가요?
You and your stupid style.
당신과 당신의 멍청한 스타일.
No one here will take you seriously if you dress like that.
당신이 그렇게 옷을 입는다면 여기 있는 어느 누구도 당신을 진지하게 받아들이지 않을 것입니다 .
Gicheul.
기철.
You gotta get up, okay?
일어나야 해, 알았지?
Do you see...
당신이 보여요...
Your asshole...
네 멍청이...
It seems losers can have tempers too.
패자도 화를 낼 수 있는 것 같습니다 .
A year has passed. Can you keep your promise now?
1년이 지났습니다. 이제 약속을 지킬 수 있나요?
Damn it.
젠장.
Have some patience, you poor ass.
좀 참아라, 이 불쌍한 놈아.
If it's hard, let me make money my own way.
힘들면 내 방식대로 돈을 벌자.
I know how
난 어떻게하는지 알아
we can all make a fortune.
우리 모두는 돈을 벌 수 있습니다.
How then?
그러면 어떻게요?
Go.
가다.
I have worked in the night life for a long time and I know
나는 오랫동안 유흥업에서 일해왔고 알고 있다.
who distributes marijuana and amphetamines.
마리화나와 암페타민을 유통하는 사람 .
If we get the little ones out of the way
어린아이들을 방해하지 않는다면
and takes over the distribution,
유통을 인수하고,
can we make good money.
우리 돈 잘 벌 수 있을까?
If you fund the plan,
계획에 자금을 지원하면
then I do the legwork.
그런 다음 발품 작업을 합니다.
Are you asking me to
나한테 부탁하는 거야?
to become a junkie?
마약 중독자가 되려고?
We only sell it.
저희는 그것만 판매합니다.
We just have to make sure our boys stay clean.
우리는 우리 아들들이 깨끗하게 지내도록 하기만 하면 됩니다 .
Bleach.
표백제.
Aha.
아하.
You fucking rich.
당신은 부자입니다.
You are crazy.
너는 미쳤어.
I am Korea's biggest boss Song Donghyuk's right hand.
나는 대한민국 최대 보스 송동혁의 오른팔이다.
And you say I have to sell drugs?
그런데 내가 약을 팔아야 한다고 하던가요?
Do you think I'm a lousy bully?
내가 형편없는 깡패라고 생각하시나요?
I'm Sergeant Jang.
저는 장 상사입니다.
Not a drug dealer.
마약상이 아닙니다.
I'm the president of Gangnam, Sergeant Jang, you idiot.
나는 강남사장이다 장병장 멍청아
Do you have a death wish or what?
죽고 싶은 소원이 있나요?
You there.
거기 당신.
Be careful what you say.
말을 조심하세요.
I'm warning you.
난 너에게 경고하는거야.
What an annoying guy.
정말 짜증나는 사람이군요.
Jang, that pig.
장, 저 돼지.
He promised us a Mercedes.
그는 우리에게 메르세데스를 약속했습니다.
Damn it!
젠장!
We're fucking rich so he can treat us like shit.
우리는 존나 부자라서 그 사람이 우리를 쓰레기처럼 대할 수 있어.
But he can't treat Gicheul like that.
하지만 기철을 그런 식으로 대할 수는 없다.
We are all here because of Gicheul.
우리는 모두 기철이 때문에 여기까지 왔습니다.
But those assholes don't respect him.
하지만 그 바보들은 그를 존경하지 않습니다.
Is your face okay?
얼굴은 괜찮아요?
are you ok
괜찮으세요
With living like this.
이렇게 살아가면서.
We're okay, dammit.
우린 괜찮아, 젠장.
We were rooting for you no matter what.
우리는 무슨 일이 있어도 당신을 응원하고 있었습니다.
He is right.
그가 옳다.
We would even follow you to Hell.
우리는 심지어 당신을 지옥까지 따라갈 것입니다.
We'd even dig up shit for you.
우리는 심지어 당신을 위해 똥을 파낼 것입니다.
It's sticky, you freak.
끈적끈적해, 이 괴물아.
Come on, let's do it.
자, 해보자.
Do what?
무엇을 합니까?
Damn it!
젠장!
- Hello. - Honey, I'll be ready tomorrow.
- 안녕하세요. - 여보, 내일 준비할게요.
Let's do it tomorrow, okay?
내일 하자, 응?
Treasure.
보물.
I'll make you happy tomorrow.
내일은 내가 행복하게 해줄게
So just rest today, okay?
그러니까 오늘은 좀 쉬어, 알았지?
Tomorrow you better...
내일은 좀 나아지길...
Damn bitch!
젠장!
Hey what's up?
무슨 일이야?
Your favorite hotel in Jeongseon for holidays.
휴가철 정선에서 가장 선호하는 호텔입니다.
Is it in the mountains?
산 속에 있나요?
Yes, it's in the middle of a forest.
네, 숲 한가운데 있어요.
It has lots of fresh air.
신선한 공기가 많이 있습니다.
Give me their information.
정보를 알려주세요.
He killed a man in middle school
그는 중학교 때 남자를 죽였습니다
and has been inside for five years.
그리고 그 안에 5년 동안 있었어요.
It's him.
그 사람이에요.
I already told him about us,
나는 이미 그에게 우리에 대해 말했어요.
so I'll let you two talk alone.
그러니 둘이서만 얘기하도록 할게요.
RECRUIT KNIVES
모집용 칼
I am Jung Gicheul.
저는 정기철입니다.
You have something inside.
당신 안에 뭔가가 있습니다.
You have something too.
당신에게도 뭔가가 있습니다.
What can you do for me?
나를 위해 뭘 해 줄 수있어?
Two clubs in Gangnam.
강남에 클럽이 2개 있습니다.
Appointment.
약속.
Let's exterminate those pigs
저 돼지들을 멸종시키자
and take over Gangnam.
그리고 강남을 점령하세요.
THE NEW JEONGSEON HOTEL
더뉴정선호텔
Is it here?
여기인가요?
PRESIDENT JANG'S TRIP FOR THE RELIEF ASSOCIATION
장 회장의 구호회 방문
- Eat up. - Thank you sir.
- 먹어라. - 감사합니다.
Hr. Jung Gicheul.
시간 정기철.
You are terrible at football!
당신은 축구를 정말 못해요!
It is okay. There is always a next time.
괜찮아. 항상 다음이 있습니다.
You were really miserable.
당신은 정말 비참했어요.
Enjoy the food, friends.
맛있게 드세요, 친구들.
Ten, Kwon Taeho.
텐, 권태호.
Year.
년도.
Where is the owner?
주인은 어디에 있나요?
He said he wouldn't interrupt and that we should enjoy ourselves.
그는 방해하지 않을 것이며 우리가 즐겁게 지내야 한다고 말했습니다.
He will come tomorrow morning to say hello.
그는 내일 아침 에 인사하러 올 것이다.
Bleach?
표백제?
By the way,
그런데,
why are there no other guests?
왜 다른 손님이 없나요?
He said that is normal in the off season.
그는 비수기에는 그것이 정상이라고 말했다.
So the owner was your middle school baseball coach?
그럼 주인이 중학교 야구부 코치였나요?
Yes, his family is very rich.
네, 그의 가족은 매우 부자입니다.
He said if you like the place,
그 곳이 마음에 든다면,
he would like some help next year
그 사람은 내년에 도움이 좀 필요해
with the new hotel construction in Gangnam.
강남에 새로운 호텔이 건설되면서
Okay. Say I'll keep it in the back of my mind.
좋아요. 마음 속에 간직하겠다고 말해요.
Bleach.
표백제.
Next.
다음.
You assholes!
이 멍청아!
Shit pigs!
젠장 돼지!
Before hell!
지옥 전에!
You little rats! I'll kill you all!
이 작은 쥐들아! 다 죽여버릴 거야!
You assholes!
이 멍청아!
Before hell!
지옥 전에!
Shit pigs.
젠장 돼지들아.
You assholes!
이 멍청아!
Move, you pig!
움직여, 돼지야!
What the hell is all this?
이게 다 뭐야?
Do people from Seoul never sleep at night?
서울 사람들은 밤에 잠도 안 자나요?
Kill them all.
그들 모두를 죽일.
Wipe them out!
그들을 닦아내세요!
Kill them all!
그들 모두를 죽일!
Kill them!
그들을 죽여 버려!
Skidrich!
스키드리치!
Chef!
요리사!
Damn it.
젠장.
Celebrate...
축하하다...
Before hell!
지옥 전에!
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
Okay.
좋아요.
Fine.
괜찮은.
Before hell.
지옥 전에.
So that's enough, okay?
그럼 그걸로 충분해, 알았지?
You can have Gangnam.
강남을 가질 수 있습니다.
Take it.
가져.
I've taken care of things outside.
나는 바깥 일을 처리했습니다.
Thanks. Then finish.
감사해요. 그런 다음 마무리하십시오.
Okay.
좋아요.
What now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
Fine.
괜찮은.
Get your hands off me.
나한테서 손 떼세요.
Hands off, I said.
나는 말했다.
Move, you pig!
움직여, 돼지야!
You little...
이 작은...
Hey, asshole.
이봐, 멍청아.
Do you have a death wish?
죽고 싶은 마음이 있나요?
Can't you see what's going on?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 볼 수 없나요?
Taeho, no. Do not!
태호, 아니야. 하지 마라!
You fucking rich.
당신은 부자입니다.
I told you to get your hands off.
손 떼라고 했어요.
- Taeho! - You bastard.
- 태호! - 이 개자식.
Let go, you pig!
놔, 돼지야!
Let go of me, you asshole!
날 놔, 이 멍청아!
I will kill you all.
나는 너희 모두를 죽일 것이다.
You are all dead now.
이제 여러분은 모두 죽었습니다.
My men from Busan are coming for you!
부산에서 내 부하들이 당신을 찾으러 옵니다!
In assholes.
멍청이들.
Give me the damn watch
빌어먹을 시계 나한테 줘
what dead pigs have.
죽은 돼지가 가지고 있는 것.
It's my damn watch, your…
그건 내 시계야, 네???
I said...
나는 말했다...
What...
무엇...
You fucking...
빌어먹을...
Your damn...
젠장...
You miserable asshole!
이 비참한 새끼야!
Die, you miserable asshole!
죽어라 이 비참한 새끼야!
BUSAN, SOUTH KOREA
대한민국 부산
I am pleased, Mr.
기쁘네요, 미스터.
My name is Jung Gicheul.
제 이름은 정기철이에요.
Sergeant Jang became blood brothers with the Jaegeon group's Sung Kisoo recently.
장병장은 최근 재건그룹 성기수와 의형제를 맺었다.
I overheard their conversation while they were drinking.
나는 그들이 술을 마시고 있는 동안 그들의 대화를 우연히 들었다.
He cuts all ties to Busan
부산과의 모든 관계를 끊다
and will start over under Sung Kisoo in Seoul.
그리고 서울에서 성기수 밑에서 다시 시작하게 됩니다.
If you wouldn't believe me,
당신이 내 말을 믿지 않는다면,
I have taken a picture.
나는 사진을 찍었다.
It wouldn't be so complicated if he were here.
그가 여기 있었다면 그렇게 복잡하지는 않았을 텐데 .
But I can't get hold of him.
하지만 나는 그 사람을 붙잡을 수가 없어요.
What did you do to him?
그 사람에게 무슨 짓을 한 거야?
Did you bury him on a mountain
그를 산에 묻었느냐
or...
또는...
Did you throw him into the sea?
그를 바다에 던졌나요?
While we brought him to Seoul,
우리가 그를 서울로 데려오는 동안,
he suddenly ran away.
그는 갑자기 도망쳤다.
We don't know where he is either.
우리도 그가 어디에 있는지 모릅니다.
He killed his own family.
그는 자신의 가족을 죽였습니다.
I just came from the funeral.
방금 장례식에서 왔습니다.
Whether he betrayed or killed someone,
누군가를 배신했든, 죽였든,
is he still one of mine
그 사람 아직도 내 사람이야?
If you wanted to get rid of him, you should have asked for permission.
그 사람을 없애고 싶다면 허락을 구했어야 했어요.
It doesn't work the other way around. It is wrong.
그 반대의 경우에는 작동하지 않습니다. 그건 잘못 됐어.
And yet
그럼에도 불구하고
you came here of your own free will.
당신은 당신의 자유 의지로 여기에 왔습니다.
What was your name?
당신의 이름은 무엇입니까?
Young Gicheul.
영기철.
Jung Gicheul is A, an idiot,
정기철은 A 바보야.
or B, a madman.
또는 B, 미친 사람.
What if there is a C?
C가 있으면 어떻게 되나요?
If you take me in,
나를 데려가면,
then I promise
그럼 약속할게
only taking Nonhyeon-dong and Yeoksam-dong.
논현동 과 역삼동만 타고요.
And...
그리고...
I send you 50 million won every month.
매달 5천만원씩 보내드립니다 .
You have my word.
약속 할게.
Do you even know what you are talking about?
당신이 무슨 말을 하는지 아시나요?
If you send me 50 million every month,
매달 5천만씩 보내주시면
how will you pay your men?
부하들에게 어떻게 돈을 지불할 건가요?
You must be Professor Yoon.
윤 교수님이시군요.
Are you from the prosecution or the police?
검찰쪽이신가요, 경찰쪽이 신가요 ?
I am the one who sent you the travel guide to China.
나는 당신에게 중국 여행 가이드를 보낸 사람입니다 .
It came with some gold.
그것은 약간의 금과 함께 왔습니다.
My name is Jung Gicheul.
제 이름은 정기철이에요.
SEOUL CENTRAL PROSECUTOR'S AUTHORITY
서울중앙검찰청
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm Murayama Hideaki. Tokyo Police, Narcotics Control Division.
저는 무라야마 히데아키입니다. 도쿄 경찰 마약 단속과.
Cho Changsik, Chief Prosecutor, Serious Crime Division.
중대범죄 수사부장 조창식 .
- I am pleased. - You too.
- 기쁘네요. - 너도.
When I said the drugs were too expensive,
약값이 너무 비싸다고 했더니
said the drug dealer
마약상이 말했어
that he gets the drugs
그 사람이 약을 구한다고
fra yakuzaerne i Yoshioka-gumi,
fra yakuzaerne i Yoshioka-gumi,
so he couldn't make it cheaper.
그래서 그는 그것을 더 싸게 만들 수 없었습니다.
Because the premium quality product with 99% purity
순도 99%의 프리미엄 품질의 제품이기 때문에
is imported from Korea.
한국에서 수입됩니다.
But just calm down.
하지만 진정하세요.
They say we are going to get
그들은 우리가 얻을 것이라고 말한다
over 10 kg every month from Korea.
한국에서 매달 10kg이 넘는다.
- "Over 10 kg every month from Korea." - Of course it will
- "한국에서 매달 10kg이 넘는다." -물론 그렇겠지
result in a price drop.
결과적으로 가격 하락이 발생합니다.
"This will naturally result in a price drop."
"이로 인해 자연스럽게 가격이 하락할 것입니다."
We let that drug dealer go
우린 그 마약상을 보내줬어
in return for these statements,
이 진술에 대한 대가로,
but he was murdered three days ago.
하지만 그는 사흘 전에 살해당했어요.
We suspect it was revenge from those in Yoshioka-gumi.
우리는 그것이 요시오카구미 사람들의 보복이었다고 의심합니다 .
Drug trade with Japan.
일본과의 마약 거래.
It's probably a Korean gang.
아마 한국 갱단일 겁니다.
Getting the Korean Amphetamine Cook
한국산 암페타민 요리사 구하기
and the smuggler arrested is not enough.
체포된 밀수꾼만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
There are many Yoshioka-gumi members throughout Japan.
일본 전역에는 요시오카구미 회원이 많이 있습니다 .
We must find out which member in which part and region,
어느 회원이 어느 부분, 지역에 속해 있는지 알아내야 하고 ,
that imports and distributes amf.
amf를 수입하고 유통하는 회사입니다.
And to ensure hard evidence,
그리고 확실한 증거를 확보하기 위해,
may we catch the smugglers in the act.
밀수업자를 체포할 수 있을까요?
Captured.
캡처되었습니다.
Do you have someone who fits this case?
이 경우에 맞는 사람이 있나요?
EUMSEONG, SOUTH KOREA
대한민국 음성
One who is tenacious.
끈기가 있는 사람.
Which does not stick out.
튀어 나오지 않습니다.
I know a guy.
나는 남자를 알고 있습니다.
He's a little wild,
그 사람은 좀 사나워요
men...
남자들...
He is perfect for the job.
그는 그 일에 완벽해요.
Your asshole.
네 개자식.
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
Don't interfere.
방해하지 마세요.
So refreshing.
정말 상쾌해요.
Don't want to go to Seoul?
서울에 가고 싶지 않아?
I come home a few times a month.
나는 한 달에 몇 번씩 집에 온다.
That was not what I meant.
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었습니다.
Do you want to do something new in Seoul?
서울에서 새로운 일을 하고 싶나요?
Something you haven't done before. Something a little dangerous.
당신이 이전에 해본 적이 없는 일. 뭔가 좀 위험한데요.
So that's why you're here.
그래서 그것이 당신이 여기 있는 이유입니다.
You will never come here.
당신은 여기에 오지 않을 것입니다.
You must infiltrate their group,
당신은 그들의 그룹에 침투해야합니다,
and if you see, hear about, and participate in amphetamine trafficking,
암페타민 밀매를 보고 듣고 참여한다면
then we can also catch the Japanese.
그러면 일본인도 잡을 수 있어요.
So I have to be a dirty guy to catch the dirty guys.
그러니까 더러운 놈들을 잡으려면 내가 더러운 놈이 되어야 해 .
Preach
설교
Have you ever researched this way before?
이전에 이런 식으로 연구해 본 적이 있나요 ?
Come now.
지금와.
If you want to catch thugs,
깡패를 잡고 싶다면,
then you track them. You don't become one of them.
그런 다음 추적합니다. 당신은 그들 중 하나가 될 수 없습니다.
Come on, we're cops. It is degrading.
자, 우리는 경찰이에요. 그것은 굴욕적이다.
And when my wife's family hears about it,
그리고 아내의 가족들이 이 소식을 듣게 되면,
they will say I do crazy things
사람들은 내가 미친 짓을 한다고 말할 거야
instead of studying for the promotion exam.
승진 시험 공부 대신에 .
Amphetamine in the billions, enough to make 330,000 people affected,
수십억 개의 암페타민은 330,000명의 사람들에게 영향을 미치기에 충분합니다.
must spread across the country.
전국으로 퍼져야 합니다.
Think of your father.
아버지를 생각해 보세요.
When you hate something so much, you can't even look at it.
뭔가가 너무 싫으면 쳐다 보지도 못해요.
Forget it. I will not do it.
잊어 버려. 나는 그것을하지 않을 것이다.
There are many other officers who can do that.
그 일을 할 수 있는 다른 장교들도 많이 있습니다 .
How can I help?
내가 어떻게 도움이 될 수 있습니다?
Is Officer Park Junmo here?
박준모 경관님 계세요?
Junmo.
준모.
He's over there.
그는 저기에있어.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I heard you and NCID's Captain Seok Dohyung are like brothers.
NCID 석도형 대위와 형제 같다고 들었습니다.
A difficult high school student from Daejeon who was known for fighting.
싸움으로 유명한 대전 출신의 까칠한 고등학생 .
And a friendly police officer who steered him in the right direction.
그리고 그를 올바른 방향으로 이끌어 준 친절한 경찰관 .
I asked Captain Seok
석 선장에게 물었다.
to recommend someone suitable for this investigation,
이 조사에 적합한 사람을 추천하기 위해 ,
and he said your name right away.
그리고 그는 즉시 당신의 이름을 말했습니다.
But I have said no.
그러나 나는 거절했습니다.
All the police chiefs
경찰서장 전원이
obviously knows about the incidents at your wedding.
당신의 결혼식에서 일어난 사건 에 대해 분명히 알고 있어요 .
Even I wouldn't give a promotion
심지어 승진도 안 하겠다.
to the son of a drug addict.
마약 중독자의 아들에게.
If this case ends well,
이번 사건이 잘 마무리된다면,
you get a significant bonus and a special promotion.
상당한 보너스 와 특별 프로모션을 받게 됩니다.
You can't stay in the low ranks forever.
영원히 낮은 순위에 머물 수는 없습니다 .
Attendant Park,
박수원님,
chances like this don't come around every day.
이런 기회는 매일 오는 것이 아닙니다.
You can rise through the ranks
순위를 높일 수 있습니다.
with the help of the prosecution.
검찰의 도움으로.
Your wife has been selected for Seoul
당신의 아내는 서울로 선발되었습니다
with his promotion to police assistant.
경찰 조수로 승진했습니다.
Isn't that wonderful?
정말 멋지지 않나요?
SOUTHERN SEOUL PLAZA
남부서울플라자
Come now.
지금와.
I do so on one condition.
한 가지 조건으로 그렇게 합니다.
A condition?
조건?
Forget the bonus.
보너스는 잊어버리세요.
But I want to move up two rows.
하지만 저는 두 줄 위로 올라가고 싶습니다.
- Two rows? - Yes.
- 두 줄요? - 예.
I'm the only one who puts life on the line.
나는 생명을 걸고 있는 유일한 사람이다 .
I think I deserve it.
나는 그럴 자격이 있다고 생각합니다.
If it ends well,
잘 끝났으면,
Aren't you also rising in the ranks?
당신도 순위가 오르고 있지 않습니까?
Why...
왜...
...don't you ascend with the help of a subordinate officer?
... 하급 장교의 도움을 받아 올라가지 않겠습니까 ?
Is there any precedent?
전례가 있나요?
In 1989 to capture Im Jongseok.
1989년 임종석을 잡기 위해.
The head of the Students' National Council.
전국학생협의회 회장.
Okay.
좋아요.
Recently, amphetamine with over 95% purity
최근에는 순도 95%가 넘는 암페타민이 등장 하고 있다.
been widespread in Gangnam as in Japan.
일본과 마찬가지로 강남에도 널리 퍼졌다.
Specifically, Gangnam Crystal.
특히 강남 크리스탈.
We thought it was connected to gangsters in Gangnam,
강남의 깡패들과 연관되어 있다고 생각했는데 ,
so we did a little digging.
그래서 우리는 조금 파헤쳐 보았습니다.
Before was Jang Kyungchul,
예전에는 장경철이었는데,
also known as "Sergeant Jang", commander of the area.
해당 지역의 사령관인 '장 하사'라고도 알려져 있습니다 .
But Jung Gicheul overthrew him,
그런데 정기철이 그를 무너뜨렸고,
which Busan's Song Donghyuk disregarded.
부산의 송동혁은 이를 무시했다.
Jung Gicheul is now the leader of Gangnam Union,
정기철은 이제 강남연합회장,
and the main members of the new gang are students from Yeoksam High School.
그리고 새로운 갱단의 주요 멤버는 역삼고등학교 학생들이다.
They have been like brothers since they were very young,
그들은 아주 어렸을 때부터 형제처럼 지냈고 ,
so they have a bond like a family.
그래서 그들은 가족과 같은 유대감을 갖고 있습니다.
Therefore, we did not rely on our usual investigative methods,
그러므로 우리는 기존의 조사 방법에 의존하지 않고,
and so we planned this.
그래서 우리는 이것을 계획했습니다.
When Jung wanted to get rid of Jang,
정이 장을 없애고자 했을 때,
a member was stabbed to death.
회원이 칼에 찔려 사망했습니다.
His name was Kwon Taeho.
그의 이름은 권태호였습니다.
He was Jung Gicheul's best friend from high school.
정기철의 고등학교 시절 가장 친한 친구였다.
The members of Gangnam Union said that Sergeant Jang was the killer,
강남조합원들은 장 경사가 살인자라고 주장했고,
but since he disappeared, the case has never been solved.
하지만 그가 사라진 이후로 사건은 해결되지 않았다.
Gangnam Union...
강남유니온...
Is there anything else special about them?
그들에게는 또 다른 특별한 것이 있습니까?
Gangnam Union took power in Gangnam really fast.
강남연합은 강남에서 정말 빠르게 정권을 잡았습니다.
From the outside
바깥으로부터
it almost looks like a social club for young entrepreneurs.
거의 젊은 기업가들을 위한 사교 클럽처럼 보입니다 .
But over the past six months in Gangnam
그런데 지난 6개월 동안 강남에서
they have almost taken over all the nightclubs.
그들은 거의 모든 나이트클럽을 장악했습니다.
Where did they get all that money from?
그들은 그 돈을 다 어디서 얻었나요?
KARAOKE, LUCKY DISCO
노래방, 럭키디스코
It probably has something to do with Gangnam Crystal.
아마도 강남 크리스탈과 관련이 있을 것 같습니다 .
Junmo, you will now be Kwon Taeho's fake cousin
준모, 너는 이제 권태호의 가짜 사촌이 된다
of the same age named Kwon Seungho,
동갑내기 권승호.
and you need to be close to Gangnam Union.
그리고 강남유니언과 가까워야 합니다.
This is the backstory we made up for Kwon Seungho.
권승호를 위해 만들어낸 뒷이야기입니다 .
He works as a fisherman.
그는 어부로 일하고 있습니다.
Kwon Seungho.
권승호.
I'll take care of his backstory beforehand.
그 사람의 뒷이야기 는 내가 미리 챙겨 놓을게 .
Do not think about it.
그것에 대해 생각하지 마라.
Do you know Sikgaek in Yeoksam-dong?
역삼동 식객을 아시나요?
They recently took over that business.
그들은 최근에 그 사업을 인수했습니다.
Some of the members eat dinner there several times a week,
회원 중 일부는 일주일에 몇 번씩 그곳에서 저녁을 먹으며,
and we suppose they are high-ranking.
그리고 우리는 그들이 고위층이라고 가정합니다.
Safety is key to the success of this operation.
이 작업의 성공에는 안전이 핵심입니다 .
There may be cops who are close to the gangsters,
조폭과 가까운 경찰이 있을 수도 있고 ,
so let's be discreet from the start.
그러니까 처음부터 조심하자.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Do you take sick leave when you look so healthy?
그렇게 건강해 보이는데 병가를 냅니까?
Junmo.
준모.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
- Take care of yourself, okay? - Okay.
- 몸조심하세요, 알았죠? - 좋아요.
Get well.
좋아지다.
Asthma?
천식?
Gangnam Unions chef, Jung Gicheul.
강남유니온 셰프 정기철입니다.
According to his travel records,
그의 여행 기록에 따르면,
within the last six months,
지난 6개월 이내,
he has visited Japan and China twice.
그는 일본과 중국을 두 번 방문했습니다.
Depth?
깊이?
If they manufacture Gangnam Crystal themselves,
강남크리스탈을 직접 제작한다면,
then maybe they buy the ingredient ephedrine in China.
그렇다면 그들은 중국에서 에페드린 성분을 구입할 수도 있습니다.
Gangnam Union and Jung Gicheul.
강남유니온과 정기철.
The worst drug crime in Korean history.
대한민국 역사상 최악의 마약범죄 .
Now let's think about,
이제 생각해 봅시다.
how Kwon Seongho should
권성호는 어떻게 해야 할까?
go to Jung Gicheul first time.
처음으로 정기철한테 가봐.
Let me try my way.
내 방식대로 해보자.
GANGNAM UNION JUNG GICHEUL
강남유니온 정기철
SIKGAEK
식객
You must order something, Mr.
뭔가 주문하셔야 해요, 선생님.
I'm not here to eat.
나는 여기에 식사하러 온 것이 아니다.
I want to talk to the owner.
주인과 얘기하고 싶어요.
I am the owner. I don't know what you mean.
나는 주인이다. 무슨 말인지 모르겠어요.
I know Gangnam Union took over this place.
이곳은 강남연합회가 인수한 것으로 알고 있습니다 .
Isn't Jung Gicheul the owner?
정기철씨가 주인이 아니신가요?
Get me Jung Gicheul.
정기철 좀 데려와.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
He's over there.
그는 저기에있어.
Who are you?
누구세요?
We have customers, so get up and go.
손님이 있으니 일어나서 가세요.
If I get up, you'll end up on the floor, you rats.
내가 일어나면 넌 바닥에 쓰러질 거야, 이 쥐새끼들아.
Now just get me Jung Gicheul.
이제 정기철을 데려오세요.
What?
무엇?
Damn it. Fine.
젠장. 괜찮은.
You fucking...
빌어먹을...
Before hell.
지옥 전에.
Boss, shouldn't we eat somewhere other than Sikgaek today?
사장님 오늘은 식객 말고 다른 곳에서 먹으면 안 될까요 ?
Why?
왜?
Download Jung Gicheul.
정기철 다운로드.
Get the owner.
주인을 구하세요.
Can you hear me?
내 말 들려요?
Then get Jung Gicheul.
그럼 정기철을 잡아라.
There is obviously a madman in the making.
분명히 미친 사람이 만들어지고 있습니다.
I'll take care of it after dinner.
저녁 식사 후에 처리하겠습니다.
Who is he?
그는 누구입니까?
SIKGAEK
식객
No, stop!
멈추지 않음!
Don't throw it away.
버리지 마십시오.
He wants to talk to Gicheul.
그는 기철과 대화하고 싶어한다.
Me?
나?
Yes, boss.
예 보스.
Why?
왜?
Those kinds of guys never say why.
그런 놈들은 절대 이유를 말하지 않죠.
Just forget it.
그냥 잊어 버리세요.
Who the hell is that?
대체 저 사람은 누구야?
Fucking idiots.
빌어먹을 바보들.
Get the boss.
상사를 잡아라.
Let's examine it.
그것을 조사해보자.
Crazy people need a lesson.
미친 사람들에게는 교훈이 필요합니다.
Get Jung Gicheul!
정기철을 잡아라!
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
I heard you were looking for me.
당신이 나를 찾고 있다고 들었습니다.
Why are you so hard to meet?
왜 이렇게 만나기 힘든 걸까요?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Are you Jung Gicheul?
Jung Gicheul입니까?
Let me go, you asshole.
날 놔줘, 이 멍청아.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Texts by: Sidsel Seeberg
글: Sidsel Seeberg